JOHN JANG

Product Designer

+1 647 553 3499

iscolbe9675@gmail.com

https://www.iohniang.ca/

in/iohniana94

SUMMARY

A Product Designer, graduated fresh from York University in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, actively developing a career in crafting user experience while carrying a year of experience in web development. Coming with a background in Neuroscience, Education, and Software Development, I have been participating in the process of building digital products either from the scratch or by redesigning what already exists, while considering the development perspective such as the User Interface development. Despite short periods of involvement in the past projects, I have been successful in delivering the results that meet the expectations of stakeholders. My strengths include strategic designing, initiating projects, and leading communications with internal and external teams. By nature, I am analytical, perceptive, and enjoy problem-solving. Outside of work, I am a runner, dancer, and a potential traveler.

EXPERIENCE

Product Designer Internship The Sakhi

06 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- Designed culturally specific shopping experience in the pilot phase
- Conducted regular design critique sessions with Shopify developers to refine features and functionality based on feedback
- Identified 8+ user flow pain points and improved the shopping experience through data-driven adjustments aligned with business goals

UX/UI Design Apprentice

TeleVU Innovation

06 / 2022 ~ 08 / 2022 | Remote, Toronto

- Conducted user research with 30 participants gathering insights that informed feature prioritization and usability
- Revamped video call service design, driving a 60% rise in call duration

Store Staff

Loblaw Companies Ltd

10 / 2021 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- Implemented an electronic navigation map to reduce the time spent on looking for products among Loblaw shoppers by 20%
- Maintained proper stock management and actively participated in sales to keep up the record sale of 25% every quarter

English as a Second Language Instructor Miller English Academy

02 / 2021 ~ 08 / 2021 | Remote, Toronto

English as a Second Language Instructor Sogang University

02 / 2020 ~ 01 / 2021 | Remote, Toronto

VOLUNTEER

Product Designer

OperateEase

09 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

Developed a comprehensive design system to

standardize UI components and hosted UX Design workshops to align with stakeholders and gather insights from users

- Led the design of an inventory management system, optimizing room occupancy and supply management, increasing efficiency by 60% from the usability tests
- Collaborated closely with engineering teams to ensure design feasibility

Web Development Apprentice Tech Fleet Professional Association

08 / 2023 ~ 09 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

 Collaborated with UX designers to develop user-friendly applications, ensuring design integrity alongside development teams

UX/UI Design Apprentice Tech Fleet Professional Association

04 / 2023 ~ 07 / 2023 | Remote, Toronto

EDUCATION

UX Design York University

University North York, Ontario

Web Development Bootcamp **Dream Coding Academy**

September 2022 ~ July 2023

Remote, Toronto

Psychology & Neuroscience University of New Brunswick

September 2013 ~ June 2017

Fredericton, NB

TOOLS & SKILLS

Figma, Figjam, Miro, Wireframing, Sketching, Typography, Prototyping, Mock-ups, A/B Testing, Usability Testing Waterfall, User-Interface Design, User Research HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, React, Vite, MongoDB, Express.js, Axios

OTHER LINKS & INFO

My Web Development Portfolio
My Github Profile

Portfolio password: portfolio